{
  "title": "Module 3: Marriage and Family Life",
  "questions": [
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "According to Grisez, marriage's ordination to procreation sets its essential requirements in the sense that:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Polygamy may be tolerated because the duty to procreate takes precedence over marital fidelity.",
        "B": "The long, involved process of raising children to maturity requires a stable, loving environment.",
        "C": "The fact that the sterile cannot fulfill marriage's primary purpose means they cannot truly marry.",
        "D": "Option 2 and Option 3"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "B",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "According to Grisez, the practice of arranged marriage can prevent the formation of valid marital bonds, such as when:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "The parties are mistaken about the indissolubility of marriage, but do not exclude it by a positive act. ",
        "B": "The spouses themselves consent to the arrangements made on their behalf and cooperate in them.",
        "C": "Marriage customs give no importance to the woman's consent, making marriage a mere transaction. ",
        "D": "Option 1 and Option 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "According to St. Augustine, marriage is good:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Finally, in as much as marriage is an end to which other human activity is directed, and is thus a principle for human action.",
        "B": "Intrinsically, insofar as people judge marriage to be personally fulfilling and so choose marriage for its own sake.",
        "C": "Instrumentally, insofar as it helps realize other goods such as the procreation of offspring and avoids evils such as sexual sin ",
        "D": "Instrumentally, insofar as it helps realize other goods such as the procreation of offspring and avoids evils such as sexual sin."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "D",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "Especially since the Second Vatican Council, the Catholic theological tradition has understood marriage to be:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "An instrumental good, inferior to virginity but nevertheless praiseworthy as a means of begetting offspring and avoiding sexual sin.",
        "B": "An intrinsic evil, since it resulted in procreation and thereby perpetuated the cycle of reincarnation by preventing the ascent of souls.",
        "C": "An intrinsic good, founded upon spousal love and for this reason characterized by fidelity, permanence, and an openness to children.",
        "D": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "In a Catholic perspective, heterosexual unions of the sterile are:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "True marriages, since the expression of conjugal love through sexual cooperation is an intrinsic good.",
        "B": "True marriages, since coitus unites spouses bodily and organically, whether or not conception results.",
        "C": "Not true marriages, since their intercourse is non-generative and for this reason merely masturbatory.",
        "D": "Option 1 and Option 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "D",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "In a Catholic perspective, homosexual unions are not as comprehensive as marriages are, since:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Homosexuals are incapable of accepting children as gifts of God and instead treat them as entitlements.",
        "B": "Heterosexual couples experience sexual pleasure as a single entity, in virtue of their organic bodily union.",
        "C": "Homosexual intercourse does not unite the parties organically in the pursuit of bodily goods in common.",
        "D": "Option 2 and Option 3"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "In a Catholic perspective, procreation perfects marriage in the sense that:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Couples remain only putatively married until they have conceived a child together.",
        "B": "Having children gives men a reason to stay committed to women they do not love.",
        "C": "Procreation unfolds marital love, giving it new avenues for expression and growth.",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "The fact that marriage is a commitment to the good of one's spouse means it is a _______ good, while the fact that it involves cooperation toward the realization of bodily goods means it is a _______ good.",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Substantive / Intelligible",
        "B": "Existential / Substantive",
        "C": "Substantive / Existential",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "B",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "The Second Vatican Council did not repeat the classical distinction between primary and secondary ends of marriage because: ",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Identifying and ranking ends (or purposes) of marriage would have suggested marriage was merely a means, not an end in itself. ",
        "B": "It was not necessary to emphasize the secondary importance of love, since few people saw this as an important feature of marriage. ",
        "C": "Affirming marriage's orientation to procreation would have complicated the Council's plans to authorize the use of contraceptives.",
        "D": "Option 1 and Option 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "A",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "To speak of marriage as an open-ended community, as Grisez does, means that:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Marriage is not intrinsically monogamous, given the sociological fact of polygamy.",
        "B": "It is impossible to bind oneself to another irrevocably, since the future is uncertain.",
        "C": "Marriage is an unreserved commitment to the good of one's spouse, come what may. ",
        "D": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.1,
      "question": "When Grisez says that couples cannot make their marital union exclusive and permanent, he means that:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "It is bad if spouses are unfaithful or divorce, but their situation can be approved if they repent for a time.",
        "B": "Marriage must be subjected to intense social pressures in order to elicit good behavior and curb infidelity.",
        "C": "These qualities are not subject matter for negotiation, but derive from the very nature of marriage itself.",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "Catholic parents should help their children prepare for the sacrament of confirmation by:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Not insisting that the children attend Mass on Sundays, so that their decision to attend will be genuinely free.",
        "B": "Teaching them new languages in anticipation of their receiving charismatic gifts, especially speaking in tongues.",
        "C": "Helping children understand their gifts and limitations, and how these can be used in the service of the gospel.",
        "D": "Option 1 and Option 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "Divorced or separated parents should cooperate in their children's personal formation by:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Preferring a full custody arrangement to shared custody, to relieve one of the parents of the burdens of child care.",
        "B": "Teaching children what a good spouse should be like by explaining how the other parent caused the marriage to fail.",
        "C": "Discuss the children's behavioral problems with one another and enforce similar discipline in their respective homes.",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "Illegitimate uses of parental authority in respect of children's vocational discernment could include:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Sending a child proficient in chemistry to a science high school rather than one specializing in the arts.",
        "B": "Conditioning financial support for the child's college education on his or her pursuing a certain major.",
        "C": "Forbidding a child from entering consecrated life, so that he or she might take over the family business.",
        "D": "Option 2 and Option 3"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "D",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "In a Catholic perspective, a child whose parents order him or her to lie in order to help the parents evade the consequences of wrongdoing appropriately honors them (Ex. 20:12) by:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Lying, since children are subject to their parents' authority and thus ought to obey them in all things",
        "B": "Lying, but in a way which exaggerates the parents' guilt, as retribution for pressuring the child to lie.",
        "C": "Refusing to lie, since parental authority lacks all force insofar as it is invoked as an incitement to sin.",
        "D": "Option 1 and Option 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "C",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "In a Catholic perspective, parents' responsibility for educating their children is best described as:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Secondary, since children's wellbeing implicates the common good, the responsibility for which vests chiefly in the state.",
        "B": "Primary, since they brought their children into the world, but cannot do everything necessary to raise them themselves.",
        "C": "Exclusive, since parents are accountable to Go alone and no authority outside the family is competent to judge them.",
        "D": "All of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "B",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "In a Catholic perspective, the right of children to an adequate moral formation obliges parents to:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Give their children anything they ask for, since this will help children learn by making their own mistakes.",
        "B": "Appeal to rational motives for choosing what is good while avoiding invocations of authority, if possible.",
        "C": "Control their children's environment to some extent, as by removing potential bad influences upon them.",
        "D": "Option 2 and Option 3"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "D",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "Parents can help children develop their ability to reason and make responsible choices by:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Involving children in the planning of meals and in purchasing and preparing ingredients.",
        "B": "Working long hours or leaving off certain household chores, to teach them resilience.",
        "C": "Refusing even children's reasonable requests without explanation, to teach them docility.",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "A",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "Parents would violate MR2 (\"Do not act individualistically for the sake of intelligible goods\") by:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Improving their children's chances of getting into a good university by doing their homework for them.",
        "B": "Refusing a child's offer to help with chores because his or her involvement would slow down the work",
        "C": "Reserving most of their paychecks for family expenses and giving their children only a small allowance.",
        "D": "Option land Option 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "D",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "Parents would violate MRS (\"Do not show partiality unless such is required by intelligible goods themselves\") by:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Spending surplus money on dental work for themselves, rather than buying their child a new video game console.",
        "B": "Excluding a gay or lesbian child from family events to which his or her heterosexual siblings are invited.",
        "C": "Not attending one child's college graduation because of a medical emergency involving his or her sibling.",
        "D": "All of the above."
      },
      "correctAnswer": "B",
      "explanation": ""
    },
    {
      "module": "Module 3",
      "section": 3.5,
      "question": "Parents' responsibility for their children's religious formation obliges them to:",
      "choices": {
        "A": "Select a good godparent, prioritizing candidates who can improve the family's finances or prestige.",
        "B": "Defer baptism and religious instruction until they are old enough to decide about these matters themselves.",
        "C": "Send their children to a Catholic school, even if its curriculum and policies openly contradict the Catholic faith.",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "D",
      "explanation": ""
    }
  ]
}